♪～
（ダルイ）雲に２つの光ありと
うたわれた→
My apologies for embarrassing you,
Kinkaku and Ginkaku,
金角　銀角様に
恥かかせちまって　すみません。
long revered as
the shining light of the Cloud.
大先輩に失礼だけど
もう少し　恥かいてもらうっす。
I don't mean to disrespect you,
but I'll have to
shame you some more.
お二人の　金と銀のメッキを→
I may end up taking the shine
out of your silver and gold...
剥がすことに
なるかもしれません。
俺の嵐遁で　一気にね！
ダルイっすけど。
With one strike of my Gale Style!
Even though this is drab...
♪～
（エー）うぅ～。
（綱手）落ち着け　雷影…
お前は　総大将だぞ。
Calm down, Raikage.
You are the Supreme Commander.
お前は　金銀兄弟の怖さを
知らんからだ！
You just don't know how frightening
the Gold and Silver Brothers are.
お前が　怖いという言葉を
知っているとはな。
I can't believe I just heard
you say the word "frightening."
フンッ…
恐怖しているわけではない。
It's not that I'm scared...
やつらは　雲隠れの歴史において
最悪の大罪人だ。
They are the most reviled criminals
in the history of the Hidden Cloud.
かつて
木ノ葉と同盟を結ぶ儀式の際→
The brothers staged
a coup d'état during
クーデターを起こして
二代目雷影と　二代目火影を→
the alliance ceremony
with the Hidden Leaf
and attacked the Second Raikage
and Second Hokage.
騙し討ちにした兄弟だぞ。
六道仙人の宝具と呼ばれる
５つの忍具を操り→
It is said they use four of
the Treasured Tools
of the Sage of Six Paths.
二代目火影を瀕死に追い込んだ
ことまでは　知っているが…。
They left the Second Hokage
near death. I know that much.
((青：なんだ　この２人は！？
What?! These two are bathed
in the Nine Tails' chakra!
(九尾のチャクラを　帯びているぞ！
すごい　チャクラだ！))
Incredible chakra!
九尾のチャクラ…。
The Nine Tails' chakra...
I didn't know they possessed it.
それを持っているとは
知らなかった。
昔　一度　雲隠れが→
Long ago, it seems the Hidden Cloud
made an attempt
九尾を捕まえようとしたことが
あったそうだ。
to capture the Nine Tails...
その時　九尾に食われたのが
金銀兄弟らしい。
and the Nine Tails
apparently devoured
the Gold and Silver Brothers.
だが　腹の中で暴れ続ける２人に
たまりかねた九尾は→
But the brothers kept
thrashing around in its belly,
forcing the Nine Tails
to vomit them.
２人を吐き出したそうだ。
それ以後　２人は
九尾のチャクラを宿してしまった。
Ever since then,
they have been infused
with the Nine Tails' chakra.
なんせ　２週間も
九尾の腹の中にいたんだからな。
Not surprising, considering they
were inside the Nine Tails' belly
for two weeks.
信じがたい話だな。
It's hard to believe, but what
about the rumors that they are
だが　六道仙人の宝具を
自在に操れるという伝説が→
able to wield the Treasured Tools
of the Sage of Six Paths?
真実だとすれば…。
宝具は　ただの人間には扱えぬ。
Normal humans cannot handle
the Treasured Tools.
あれらを扱うと
大量のチャクラを吸いとられ→
They absorb massive amounts
of chakra from its user
普通のものは死ぬ。
that would kill the average man.
九尾のチャクラを宿した
バケモノのような輩以外にはな。
Except ones who harbor
the Nine Tails' chakra,
like those two monsters.
バケモノじみたチャクラを持ち
敵も味方も　九尾さえも恐れず→
They are shinobi
with monstrous chakra
who wreak havoc and fear nothing,
not even the Nine Tails.
ただ　暴れるだけの忍。
わしが　怖いと思うのは→
What scares me is
the thought of our subordinates
そんなやつを相手にせねばならん
部下たちを思えばこそだ。
who must face them...
it's infinite, it's infinite, it's infinite, rock assault
eien desu eien desu eien desu totsugeki rock
I was asleep all this time, I kept quiet all this time
zutto nemutteta zutto damatteta
hey, it's calling us, hey, let's go
ooi yonde iru ooi itte mi yo
I can see something far away
tooku ni nanika ga mieru
something more important now than studying
benkyou yori mo ima taisetsu na mono
hey, it's calling us, hey, let's go
ooi yonde iru ooi itte mi yo
I think we can find it
mitsukarisou nanda
it's infinite, it's infinite, it's infinite, rock assault
eien desu eien desu eien desu totsugeki rock
see, you can overtake the future
mirai wa hora oinuite
this ship can really fly through the sky
hontou wa sora toberu fune
Forbidden Words
（銀角）大先輩への口の利き方が
気に入らねえな。
I don't like that tone
you're using toward your seniors.
すぐに黙らせてやる。
I'll shut you up!
（金角）しかたねえ　どうやら
ずいぶんと時が経ってる。
It can't be helped.
Seems like a lot of time has passed.
No one knows about us anymore.
同胞でも俺たちのことを
知らねえんだからよ。
サムイさん　アツイ。
Samui, Atsui.
（サムイ）あなたたちが
書物に出てくる→
If you're really
the Gold and Silver Brothers
本物の金角　銀角なら→
we read about in our scrolls,
同胞呼ばわりされたくないわね。
don't talk to me
like we're comrades.
クールじゃないわ！
It's not cool.
（アツイ）おぉ
いつになく　クールな姉ちゃんが→
Well, well... For someone
who's always cool,
熱いじゃねえのよ！
you're quite hot right now.
相当なやつらとみた。
I sense that you guys
are pretty formidable.
やるぞ　銀角。
おうよ　金角！
Let's do this, Ginkaku!
All right, Kinkaku!
なんだ…　ありゃあ。
What is that?!
間違いない。
No doubt about it,
those are the ninja tools
書物にあった
あれが　金角銀角兄弟の忍具！
of the Gold and Silver Brothers
that were described in the scroll!
かつて　雲隠れが集めた
最強忍具の５つのうち４つ。
Four of the five
ultimate ninja tools,
which the Hidden Cloud
collected long ago.
人を縛り　言霊を追い出す
幌金縄。
The Kokinjo binds its victim and
squeezes out
the victim's spirit word!
言霊を斬って呪う　七星剣。
The Shichiseiken severs and
curses that spirit word...
言霊を録音し　人を封じる
紅葫蘆。
The Benihisago records
the spirit word
and seals the speaker with in!
火　水　雷　風　土。
And the Bashosen conjures up
all five chakra natures:
すべての性質を巻き起こせる
芭蕉扇。
fire, water, lightning,
wind and earth!
姉ちゃん　解説の途中　悪いが…。
Sorry to interrupt
your lecture, Sis, but...
（アツイ）ここは　俺に！
Let me handle this!
雲流　火炎斬り！
Cloud Style! Flame Slice!
仰々しい忍具みてえだが
所詮　道具！
Those ninja tools look nasty,
but ultimately,
they're just mere tools!
俺たちの魂のこもった
熱い忍術にゃ　かなわねえぜ！
They're no match for our ninjutsu
that's imbued with our hot souls!
アツイ　待ちな！
クールに話を最後まで！
Atsui, wait!
Stay cool until I finish!
チッ…　熱すぎる！
Damn it! He's too hot-headed!
フッ　どいつもこいつも
よくしゃべる…　いいねえ。
They talk too much...
This is perfect.
俺は　いちばん
後ろのやつをやる！
I'll take the one in the back!
わかった　銀角。
残りは任せろ！
Got it, Ginkaku!
Leave the others to me!
俺の熱い闘志を避けて
ダルイさん狙いとは！
The nerve of the guy...
Avoiding someone like me,
with a hot fighting spirit,
to go for Darui!
厚い人垣で　俺の熱い攻撃を
かわせると思ったか！
Did you think you could avoid
my hot-spirited attack
with a crowd of bodies!?
ぐわぁ…。
気を抜くな　アツイ。
クールに周りを見ろ！
Pay attention, Atsui!
Stay cool and look around you!
ぐっ　なかなか熱いパンチだぜ！
That punch was pretty hot!
フンッ。
くっ。
《しまった！》
Damn it!
アツイ　サムイさん！　大丈夫か！
Atsui, Samui! Are you all right?
よそ見してんじゃねえぞ　ガキが！
Don't look away, kid!
交代だ　金角。
了解　銀角。
Change places, Kinkaku!
Right, Ginkaku.
くっ…　敵一人止められないとは。
Can't I even stop one foe?
すまない　サムイさん　アツイ！
Forgive me, Samui, Atsui...
おっと！　今度は　俺が相手だ。
Whoa...
I'm your opponent this time!
金角のおっさんは
なかなか　熱いパンチだったぜ。
That Kinkaku fellow packed
a pretty hot punch!
今度は　銀角のおっさんのほうか。
And this time it's Ginkaku, eh?
しぼり出せ！　幌金縄！
Squeeze them!
Kokinjo!
何だ？　ありゃ！
What is that?!
この左手の幌金縄は
触れたやつの言霊をしぼり出す。
The Kokinjo in my left hand
squeezes out the Spirit Word
of anyone that touches it!
呪え！　七星剣！
Curse them! Shichiseiken!
HOT
COOL
録音しろ。
Record them!
紅葫蘆！
Benihisago!
さて　こっちは終わったぜ　金角。
All right.
My side is done, Kinkaku.
はぁ！
《やられた》
He's been struck...
That's what you think, you jerks!
何言ってんだ　てめえは！
今度は　こっちの番だ！
It's our turn now!
話は　最後まで聞きなって
言ったでしょ。
Didn't I tell you to let me finish?
いい？　これから
うかつに　しゃべらないこと。
Now listen. Don't say another word.
どういうことだ？
What do you mean?
私たちは
呪印術と封印術をかけられた。
A Curse Mark Jutsu and
Sealing Jutsu have been used on us.
言霊を人質にとられたのよ。
Our Spirit Words have
been taken hostage.
生まれて今まで
いちばん多く口にした言葉。
The word we've uttered
the most since our birth.
これを言ってしまうと→
If we say that word...
HOT
COOL
あの瓢箪の中へ吸い込まれて
封印されてしまう。
We'll be sucked into that gourd
and sealed away.
よく知ってんじゃねえか。
You know a lot, don't you?
時代が経って　いろいろ
バレちまってるみてえだな。
It seems the passage of time
revealed a lot of things.
いちばん多く口にした言葉が
タブーだと？
The word we've said
the most is now forbidden?
ＮＧワードで
ゲームしてんじゃねえんだぞ！
We're not playing
some silly word game...
だるいことしやがって！
So drab...
HOT
COOL
なるほど。
I see.
芭蕉扇！
Bashosen!
《何だ？
俺のいちばん多く口にした→
What?
What is the hot word I love
to use the most?!
熱い言葉って　何だ？》
《お前は考えなくても
だいたい　わかるだろ　たぶん》
You probably don't have
to think too hard to figure it out.
火の巻き！
Scroll of Fire!
あ…　熱い！
Hot!
うわぁ～！
Damn it!
バ…　バカ！
Stupid...
うわぁ～っ！！
アツイ！
チッ！
Atsui!
昔から　こう言う。
沈黙は金とな。
There's an old saying,
"Silence is golden."
口は災いのもとだ。
なぁ　銀角。
The mouth is
the source of calamity.
Right, Ginkaku?
ああ　金角。
ベラベラしゃべっていると　こうなる。
Yeah, Kinkaku!
This is what happens when
you can't keep your mouth shut.
言葉なんてのは　ウソで
人を騙すための道具だ。
Words are used to lie.
They're merely tools
for deceiving people.
言葉をバカにすっと
ビーさんに怒られるっすよ。
If you make fun of words,
Bee will let you have it.
ビーだぁ？　知るか　そんなやつ。
Bee? Never heard of him.
動けば　女は殺す…。
If you move, the girl dies.
これは　嘘じゃねえぞ！
And I'm not lying.
すみません…　サムイさん。
I'm sorry, Samui.
そう　くるよな…　さすが
雲隠れの忍だ　２人とも。
Just as I expected.
I must say, you're both
true Hidden Cloud shinobi.
嵐遁…　レイザーサーカス！
Gale Style!
Laser Circus!
速い！　しかも　誘導忍術か！？
He's fast.
And to top it off,
it was a Precision Ninjutsu?
ぐおっ…。
ナメるな　小僧！
Don't take us lightly, brat!
ぐっ…！
くっ…　いてて…。
Owww...
《金角のやつ
幌金縄を上手く当てたな》
Kinkaku did a good job
of applying the Kokinjo.
うっ…。
まずは　こっちだな。
This one's first.
どういうことだ？
何も言っていないのに→
What's going on?!
She didn't say a word,
but Samui's been sucked in?!
サムイさんが吸い込まれた…！？
呪え！
Curse him!
七星剣！
Shichiseiken!
《腕がもう　再生されてやがる》
His arm has already regenerated!
録音しろ　紅葫蘆！
Record him, Benihisago!
はぁ　はぁ…。
《俺のＮＧワードは
だいたい　想像できる》
I can figure out what
my forbidden word is.
((だるいっすけど！
This is drab!
(だるいことしやがって！))
That was pretty drab.
DRAB
《俺のＮＧワード…。
My forbidden word...
一生で　いちばん多く
口にした言葉は→
The word I've used most often in
my life is without a doubt,
おそらく　「だるい」だ。
"drab."
DRAB
それを口にしなければ→
As long as I don't use it...
あの瓢箪に
吸い込まれることはない。
I won't be sucked into that gourd.
だが…　サムイさんは
口にしていないのに吸い込まれた。
However... Samui didn't say a word
but she was sucked in.
このことから　おそらく…》
Which means...
一定時間　黙っていても
吸い込まれてしまう…　違うか！？
If you stay quiet for
a fixed amount of time,
you can get sucked in...
Am I right?
よく気づいたな…。
Sharp of you to notice.
ここまでは　バレてなかった
みてえだが…　なかなか　やる。
It seemed no one had
figured that out yet.
You're pretty smart.
沈黙は金　なんて
よく言えたもんだ。　ったく。
"Silence is golden"? As if...
雄弁は金　ってこともある。
They also say that,
"speech is silver"!
騙してなんぼの弁舌だ！
Especially when spoken
with a forked tongue!
ここで言うなら
沈黙は禁止の禁　ってな。
In this case, silence is
the most forbidden taboo.
ア～ッハッハッハ…。
だから言ったろ
言葉なんてのは→
Didn't I tell you?
Words are tools with which
to fool others.
人を騙すための道具だってな。
忍の世では　騙し合い
裏切りも　立派な戦術…。
In the shinobi world,
trickery and betrayal are
fine military tactics.
言葉も忍具だ。
The spoken word is also
a ninja tool.
そんなんだから…。
Is it any wonder that you two
are symbols of disgrace
雲隠れで　あんたたちは
不名誉の象徴なのさ。
among the Hidden Cloud?
くっ…　なんだと
この三下銅野郎！
How dare you say that,
you third-rate underling?!
お前は　所詮　雷影の駒で→
You're just another pawn
for the Raikage...
この忍具の
類似品みてえなもんだ。
A mere ninja tool.
タダの忍具だ！
ほざくな　甘ちゃんが！
A mere ninja tool!
So you can cut the drivel!
ったく
今どきの忍は　何様だ！
What the hell is wrong
with the ninja of today?
((ボス…　すみません。
Boss...
I'm sorry.
護衛役に選ばれていながら→
I was chosen to be your bodyguard
and yet you lost your left arm...
ボスの左腕を…。
お前が　気にすることではない。
しかし…。
Don't worry about it.
But...
左腕に未練などない。
I don't miss my left arm.
なぜなら　わしは
右腕を２つ持っておるからな。
After all, I have two right arms.
２つ？
Two?
うむ　これと…。
This and...
お前だ。
you.
どうせなら　シーも入れて
３つってのはどうっすか？
How about including Shee
and making it three?
フフッ　まあいいだろう。
Well, all right.
(多いに越したことはない))
You can never have too many.
俺は　ボスの右腕だ。
類似品じゃねえ！
I am the Boss's courageous
right-hand man...
Not some timid rabbit!
おい　銀角。
何だ　金角。
Hey, Ginkaku...
What, Kinkaku?!
紅葫蘆を構えろ。
Get ready for Benihisago.
フッ…　なるほど。
I see.
何だ！？　だるいとは言ってない！
Why?
I didn't say "drab."
((俺は　ボスの右腕だ。
類似品じゃねえ！))
I am the Boss's courageous
right-hand man.
Not some timid rabbit!
ボスの右腕だ　類似品じゃねえ！
I am the Boss's courageous
right-hand man...
Not some timid rabbit!
みぎうでだ　るいじひんじゃ…。
Timid rabbit is...
だ…　るい！
Drab!
DRAB
しまった！
Damn it!
((ダルイ…　お前に連合の
部隊長をやってもらいたい。
Darui...
I want you to be lead one of
the Allied Shinobi companies...
(わしの右腕としてな))
as my right-hand man!
すみません　ボス…。
My apologies, Boss...
《右腕と
自負していたはずなのに…》
I was so proud to be
your right-hand man...
すみません　サムイさん　アツイ。
My apologies, Samui... Atsui...
すみません　みんな…。
My apologies, everyone...
すみません　すみません　本当に。
My apologies...
My sincerest apologies...
そろそろ
あっちへ乗り込むぞ　銀角。
Ready to move on, Ginkaku?
おうよ　金角。
Right, Kinkaku.
なんで！？
Why?!
うわっ！
《しまった！
幌金縄にあたっちまった！》
Damn it!
I touched the Kokinjo!
なぜ　あいつは！？
Why didn't he...?
DRAB
APOLOGIES
♪～
俺は…。
I...
((机とか壁とか　すみませんね。
I apologize about the desks
and the wall...
雲に２つの光あり
とうたわれた→
My apologies for embarrassing you,
Kinkaku and Ginkaku,
金角　銀角様に
恥かかせちまって　すみません。
long revered as the shining light
of the Cloud.
(すみません　サムイさん))
Apologies, Samui...
《俺は　意外と
謙虚なやつだったってことか。
I guess that means
I'm a pretty humble guy.
悪くねえ》
That's not so bad.
確かに　だるいだった。
I'm certain it was "dull."
((すみません　ボス
すみません　みんな。
My apologies, Boss.
My apologies, everyone...
すみません　サムイさん　アツイ。
My apologies, Samui... Atsui...
(すみません　本当に…))
I'm so sorry.
吸い込んでる最中に
いちばん多く口にした言葉が→
Don't tell me...
While he was being sucked in,
二番目の言葉と
入れかわったと言うのか？
his most-used word switched places
with his second-most uttered word?
♪～
呪え　七星剣！
Curse him! Shichiseiken!
録音しろ　紅葫蘆！
たしか　こんな感じだったか。
Record him! Benihisago!
I think that's the way it goes!
てめぇ…。
Why you...
すっげえ　チャクラとられんな　これ。
This uses up so much... chakra...
こっちが　くたばりそうだぜ…。
I feel like I'm gonna drop first.
確かに
言葉ってのは　嘘をつき→
It's true... words can be used
as tools to trick people.
人を騙すための
道具かもしんねぇ。
けど　ここぞってとき
言葉ってのは…。
But when it really counts,
the spoken word...
((なぜなら　わしは
右腕を２つ持っておるからな。
After all, I have two right arms.
(これと　お前だ！))
This...
and you!
言葉ってのはよ→
The spoken word is...
ここの中のまことを伝える
大切なもんになる。
is a precious thing that conveys
the truth that's right here.
助けてくれ　金角…。
Help me... Kinkaku.
だからこそ　あんたは
今　封印されるのさ。
That's why I'm going
to seal you now.
KINKAKU
金角！
Kinkaku!
《サムイさん　アツイ
あんたたちのおかげだ。
Samui... Atsui...
It's all thanks to you.
後で　必ず助け出す！
さて　あとは　もう一方の…》
I swear I'll save you later.
But now... there's one more.
おのれ　よくも…。
Why you...
How dare...
よくも！
How dare you!
♪～
なんだ！？
What?!
おいおい…
これじゃ　まるで…。
Hey! Hey! Hey!
This is...!
うぅ…　貴様　よくも銀角を…。
How dare you do that
to Ginkaku...?!
まるで
九尾の人柱力じゃないか…。
He looks exactly like
the Nine Tails' Jinchuriki!
♪～
I want to overcome this cycle of regret and sadness
kurikaeshite kita ikutsu mo no koukai to kanashimi norikoe
to see what I'm really worth
jibun no kachi wo tashikamete mitainda
I'll shake off the voices around me
mawari no koe wo furi haratte
and push aside the surging crowd
muragaru hitonami kakiwakete
until I can touch that eternity I drew with you
anata to egaite kita eien ni fureru mate
even if I lose everything
tatoe subete ushinatte mo
I must move forward
susumanakya naranai
there's a door that only I can open
watashi ni shika hirakenai tobira ga aru
even if I'm hurt badly
fukaku kizutsuita to shite mo
I want to keep shouting
kono koe karashite
until I'm hoarse, I have a one and only love
sakebi tsuzuketai tatta hitotsu dake no ai ga aru
so I'll believe in this power welling up, and I'll stand
so waki agaru chikaraka wo shinjite tachiagaru
let it go, I'm beholden to this resilient life I've been given
let it go akiramene inochi moratta kari ga aru
scale mountains and valleys, for there's always something
yama ga aru tani ga aru norikoete moreba nani ga aru
live, for there's a future, there's a journey just for me
ikite ireba kono saki ga aru dare ni mo yuzurenai tabi ga aru
It's a strategy from HQ!
We'll strike Kinkaku with
the Ino-Shika-Cho Formation.
Until they get here, we'll have to
hold this location down!
– All right!
He may have the power
of the Nine Tails,
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
but we have the power of
the Ino-Shika-Cho bond!
美空ひばりです。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Golden Bonds"
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
Please hold on until
they get there!
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華歌手
１０組の皆さんによる→